<posts><row AcceptedAnswerId="509" AnswerCount="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Our nightly full (and periodic differential) backups are becoming quite large, due mostly to the amount of indexes on our tables; roughly half the backup size is comprised of indexes.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;We're using the &lt;strong&gt;Simple&lt;/strong&gt; recovery model for our backups.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Is there any way, through using &lt;code&gt;FileGroups&lt;/code&gt; or some other file-partitioning method, to &lt;strong&gt;exclude&lt;/strong&gt; indexes from the backups?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if this could be extended to full-text catalogs, as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="1" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T06:49:01.807" EntityChunks="half" FavoriteCount="3" Id="1" LastActivityDate="2009-05-10T15:22:39.707" LastEditDate="2009-05-04T02:11:16.667" LastEditorUserId="919" NounPhrases=" nightli,full  period differenti  backup becom,larg,due mostli amount index tabl,half backup size compris index     use,file partit method,index backup,full text catalog" OwnerUserId="3" PostTypeId="1" Score="17" Tags="&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;backup&gt;&lt;sql-server-2008&gt;&lt;indexes&gt;" Title="How to exclude indexes from backups in SQL Server 2008" Verbs="quit,roughli,use,would,nice,could,extend" ViewCount="4878" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="1238" AnswerCount="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;We've struggled with the RAID controller in our database server, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pc.ibm.com/europe/server/index.html?nl&amp;amp;cc=nl&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Lenovo ThinkServer&lt;/a&gt; RD120. It is a rebranded Adaptec that Lenovo / IBM dubs the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redbooks.ibm.com/abstracts/tips0054.html#ServeRAID-8k&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;ServeRAID 8k&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;We have patched this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redbooks.ibm.com/abstracts/tips0054.html#ServeRAID-8k&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;ServeRAID 8k&lt;/a&gt; up to the very latest and greatest:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;RAID bios version&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;RAID backplane bios version&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Windows Server 2008 driver&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;This RAID controller has had multiple critical BIOS updates even in the short 4 month time we've owned it, and the &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.software.ibm.com/systems/support/system_x/ibm_fw_aacraid_5.2.0-15427_anyos_32-64.chg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;change history&lt;/a&gt; is just.. well, scary. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;We've tried both write-back and write-through strategies on the logical RAID drives. &lt;strong&gt;We still get intermittent I/O errors under heavy disk activity.&lt;/strong&gt; They are not common, but serious when they happen, as they cause SQL Server 2008 I/O timeouts and sometimes failure of SQL connection pools.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;We were at the end of our rope troubleshooting this problem. Short of hardcore stuff like replacing the entire server, or replacing the RAID hardware, we were getting desperate.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;When I first got the server, I had a problem where drive bay #6 wasn't recognized. Switching out hard drives to a different brand, strangely, fixed this -- and updating the RAID BIOS (for the first of many times) fixed it permanently, so I was able to use the original &quot;incompatible&quot; drive in bay 6. On a hunch, I began to assume that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822136143&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;the Western Digital SATA hard drives&lt;/a&gt; I chose  were somehow incompatible with the ServeRAID 8k controller.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Buying 6 new hard drives was one of the cheaper options on the table, so I went for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822145215&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;6 Hitachi (aka IBM, aka Lenovo) hard drives&lt;/a&gt; under the theory that an IBM/Lenovo RAID controller is more likely to work with the drives it's typically sold with.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Looks like that hunch paid off -- we've been through three of our heaviest load days (mon,tue,wed) without a single I/O error of any kind. Prior to this we regularly had at least one I/O &quot;event&quot; in this time frame. &lt;strong&gt;It sure looks like switching brands of hard drive has fixed our intermittent RAID I/O problems!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;While I understand that IBM/Lenovo probably tests their RAID controller exclusively with their own brand of hard drives, I'm disturbed that a RAID controller would have such subtle I/O problems with particular brands of hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;So my question is, &lt;strong&gt;is this sort of SATA drive incompatibility common with RAID controllers?&lt;/strong&gt; Are there some brands of drives that work better than others, or are &quot;validated&quot; against particular RAID controller? I had sort of assumed that all commodity SATA hard drives were alike and would work reasonably well in any given RAID controller (of sufficient quality).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:04:18.883" EntityChunks="dub  ,first,first,three" FavoriteCount="2" Id="2" LastActivityDate="2015-03-15T23:55:24.003" LastEditDate="2015-03-15T23:55:24.003" LastEditorUserId="118258" NounPhrases="lenovo thinkserv,rebrand adaptec lenovo,patch,raid bio version,multipl critic bio updat,even short   month time,tri,write strategi logic raid drive,error heavi disk activ,caus sql server,timeout sometim failur sql connect pool     end rope troubleshoot problem,short hardcor stuff,replac entir,raid hardwar,desper,problem drive bay    recogn,hard drive,differ brand,strang,fix    updat raid bio,first mani time  fix,perman,abl use,origin,bay    hunch,assum  western digit,hard drive,control,new hard drive one cheaper option tabl,hard drive,theori,lenovo raid control,work drive typic,hunch,mon tue,we,singl error,prior regularli least one  event,time frame,switch,brand hard drive fix,raid problem,lenovo probabl test raid control exclus brand hard drive,raid control,incompat common raid control   brand drive work,better other   valid  particular raid control,assum commod sata hard drive alik,reason,raid control,suffici qualiti" OwnerUserId="1" PostTypeId="1" Score="22" Tags="&lt;raid&gt;&lt;ibm&gt;" Title="Do RAID controllers commonly have SATA drive brand compatibility issues?" Verbs="struggl,server,ibm,dub,write,write,get,happen,failur,connect,get,get,drive,switch,fix,drive,begin,choose,buy,go,ibm,ibm,sell,look,pay,look,understand,would,drive,would,work,give" ViewCount="3739" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="104" AnswerCount="11" Body="&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;How do you keep your servers up to date?&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;When using a package manager like &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/Aptitude&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Aptitude&lt;/a&gt;, do you keep an upgrade / install history, and if so, how do you do it?&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;When installing or upgrading packages on multiple servers, are there any ways to speed the process up as much as possible?&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:48:06.750" EntityChunks="" FavoriteCount="14" Id="3" LastActivityDate="2015-02-22T07:16:50.387" LastEditDate="2015-02-22T07:16:50.387" LastEditorUserId="118258" NounPhrases="server date,packag manag,instal upgrad packag multipl server,way,speed process" OwnerUserId="22" PostTypeId="1" Score="30" Tags="&lt;unix&gt;&lt;package-management&gt;" Title="Best practices for keeping UNIX packages up to date?" Verbs="keep,use,aptitud,keep,possibl" ViewCount="1294" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="537" AnswerCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Our database currently only has one FileGroup, PRIMARY, which contains roughly 8GB of data (table rows, indexes, full-text catalog).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;When is a good time to split this into secondary data files?  What are some criteria that I should be aware of?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:57:06.247" EntityChunks="one" FavoriteCount="2" Id="6" LastActivityDate="2009-07-08T07:23:49.527" NounPhrases="current one filegroup,primari,contain,roughli,gb data,tabl,row  index  full text catalog      good time split secondari data file   criteria awar" OwnerUserId="3" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;files&gt;&lt;groups&gt;" Title="In SQL Server, when should you split your PRIMARY Data FileGroup into secondary data files?" Verbs="databa,split" ViewCount="8777" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="17" AnswerCount="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;What enterprise virus-scanning systems do you recommend?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" ClosedDate="2012-08-06T20:15:42.223" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:57:09.117" EntityChunks="" FavoriteCount="4" Id="7" LastActivityDate="2012-08-06T20:06:15.843" NounPhrases=" enterpris,viru scan system" OwnerUserId="32" PostTypeId="1" Score="12" Tags="&lt;anti-virus&gt;" Title="What is the best enterprise virus-scanning system?" Verbs="recommend" ViewCount="866" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="38" AnswerCount="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm chasing a pipe dream here, but I'd really like to find an easy to use backup solution that supports both Windows and OS X, presumably something people never have to think about until the worst happens.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" ClosedDate="2012-01-13T04:44:48.560" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:58:11.033" EntityChunks="" FavoriteCount="2" Id="10" LastActivityDate="2010-09-02T19:27:12.807" LastEditDate="2009-05-04T02:10:53.753" LastEditorUserId="919" NounPhrases=" mayb chase pipe dream,easi,backup solut support window,presum someth peopl" OwnerUserId="27" PostTypeId="1" Score="9" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;backup&gt;&lt;mac-osx&gt;" Title="Best mixed environment (OS X + Windows) backup?" Verbs="realli,find,think,happen,suggest" ViewCount="3832" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="394" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;[This was originally posted at stackoverflow.com but might be more suitable here and I'm sure it's a server configuration issue. Apologies if this is considered bad form.]&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;As part of our database revision control (and auto-installation) procedures we need to be able run sqlcmd.exe on various .sql files from within an ASP page. The code I'm using to do this is:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dim cmd : cmd = &quot;sqlcmd -S &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_SERVER &amp;amp; &quot; -U &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_UID &amp;amp; &quot; -P &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_PWD &amp;amp; &quot; -d &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_NAME &amp;amp; &quot; -i &quot;&quot;&quot; &amp;amp; scriptPath &amp;amp; &quot;&quot;&quot; -b&quot;&#10;Dim wshShell : Set wshShell = Server.CreateObject(&quot;WScript.Shell&quot;)&#10;Dim return : return = wshShell.Run(cmd, 0, True)&#10;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I have the code working fine on two separate development machines. These are both running XP and required no additionally steps to get the code working. Having deployed the code to a Windows 2003 server it's having problems. The problem being that the value for return is always 1. This also happens if I try to get it to run a batch file or anything else I can think of (if I change the value for cmd to an non-existing file it bombs out as I'd expect)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I've tried adding I_USR and I_WAM to have execute permissions on both sqlcmd.exe and cmd.exe but it still returns 1. If I open a command prompt at the server and do a &quot;runas /user:servername\i_usr sqlcmd.exe&quot; that works fine but running from the ASP page still doesn't work.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Also, when running the .sql scripts manually everything runs smoothly so there's no problem with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Are there any security settings on the server that I've forgotten to change within IIS or Windows generally to make it work?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I have also tried this on another Server 2003 machine and am getting exactly the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Halp.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:59:31.013" EntityChunks="two" Id="12" LastActivityDate="2009-06-17T00:21:54.520" LastEditDate="2009-06-17T00:21:54.520" LastEditorUserId="3038" NounPhrases="  origin post stackoverflow com,sure server configur issu,apolog consid bad form      part,databas revis control,procedur,sqlcmd exe variou  sql file,asp page,code use,dim,cmd    sqlcmd     amp,databas server,amp,amp,amp,databas pwd,amp,amp,databas name,amp,amp,scriptpath,amp,wshshell   set wshshell   server,wscript shell   dim return   return,wshshell,two separ,machin,xp requir addit step,code work,code window      server problem,problem valu return,batch file,anyth els,chang,non exist file bomb,tri ad usr wam execut,sqlcmd exe cmd exe,sqlcmd exe,fine run asp page,sql script manual everyth,smoothli problem     secur,set server forgotten chang,ii window gener,work,also tri,machin,problem" OwnerUserId="39" PostTypeId="1" Score="1" Tags="&lt;windows-server-2003&gt;&lt;windows&gt;" Title="Running an .exe from an .asp file using wscipt under Windows Server 2003" Verbs="may,suitabl,consid,revi,need,run,cmd,wshshell,return,run,cmd,work,develop,run,get,happen,get,run,think,cmd,exist,expect,return,work,work,run,sql,run,set,forget,make,server,get" ViewCount="680" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="152" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;My System is a Ubuntu 7.10. I have a (soft) RAID 6 with 5 disks (Samsung 500GB SATA disks), formatted with jfs. Should I upgrade to 8.10 or isn't it worth the hassle? What are the chances that something could happen to the RAID configuration? I don't want to be in the position to rebuild the RAID from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:00:58.000" EntityChunks="" Id="15" LastActivityDate="2015-08-20T02:41:42.253" LastEditDate="2015-08-20T02:41:42.253" LastEditorUserId="1375" NounPhrases="soft  raid     disk,samsung,gb sata disk   format,jf,raid configur" OwnerUserId="44" PostTypeId="1" Score="2" Tags="&lt;linux&gt;&lt;ubuntu&gt;&lt;raid&gt;" Title="(Soft) RAID 6 on Ubuntu 7.10, should I migrate to 8.10?" Verbs="chanc,could,happen,rebuild,scratch" ViewCount="479" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="22" AnswerCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a website that a number of customers are using to host their sites.  They each have their own domain name, but are using the same hosted service.  Is it better to have them run off the same IIS website with all the host headers on that site, or should I create a different website &amp;amp; app pool for each domain that point at the same physical directory on the server?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:00:58.220" EntityChunks="" FavoriteCount="2" Id="16" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T04:25:18.430" LastEditDate="2009-05-01T04:25:18.430" LastEditorUserId="38" NounPhrases=" websit number custom,host site   domain name,use,ii websit host header site,creat differ websit,amp,app,pool domain point physic directori server" OwnerUserId="38" PostTypeId="1" Score="7" Tags="&lt;iis&gt;&lt;hosting&gt;&lt;web-hosting&gt;" Title="Are there any issues with having multiple IIS websites pointing at the same folder?" Verbs="servic,run,creat" ViewCount="2664" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="32" AnswerCount="21" Body="&lt;p&gt;What's the top the reason you're unable - or unwilling - to upgrade to the latest available operating system verions?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" ClosedDate="2012-10-21T16:34:09.213" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:04:57.850" EntityChunks="" FavoriteCount="2" Id="21" LastActivityDate="2012-10-21T16:19:42.710" LastEditDate="2009-05-25T13:47:41.273" LastEditorUserId="2546" NounPhrases=" top reason,latest avail oper system verion" OwnerUserId="32" PostTypeId="1" Score="18" Tags="&lt;operating-system&gt;" Title="What prevents you from upgrading to newer operating system versions?" Verbs="unwil" ViewCount="500" />
  <row AcceptedAnswerId="34" AnswerCount="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am looking for open source applications that will allow resizing hard drive partitions. I have used partition magic in the past but am looking for open source free applications that can handle this task.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" ClosedDate="2014-02-24T00:36:56.233" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:06:27.020" EntityChunks="" FavoriteCount="4" Id="23" LastActivityDate="2015-03-23T21:12:06.127" LastEditDate="2015-03-23T21:12:06.127" LastEditorUserId="118258" NounPhrases="resiz hard drive partit,partit magic,open sourc free applic handl task" OwnerUserId="2" PostTypeId="1" Score="11" Tags="&lt;partition&gt;" Title="Open source applications for resizing drive partitions" Verbs="look,allow,use,look" ViewCount="516" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;It sounds as if this isn't supported. From this &lt;a href=&quot;https://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/ViewFeedback.aspx?FeedbackID=331220&amp;amp;wa=wsignin1.0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;bug report info&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;There's been a lot of interest in this one, so I'll go into a bit more detail as to what is happening behind the scenes, and what it would mean to implement this functionality.&#10;  Some types of index pages are segregated into separate allocation units, while others are mixed in with the data pages.&#10;  Where we currently only look at the allocation bitmap to see if an extent is allocated, now we would have to go in and interpret what is stored in each allocation unit. Further, we would now not be able to just do a linear scan of the data files copying data, we'd be skipping around in the file.&#10;  All of this interpretation of the data structures would drastically slow down backup. Restore gets even more interesting, because there are a lots of structures that would have to ba fixed up to account for the holes in the backup. Otherwise you'd have allocation maps pointing to pages which weren't backed up, and so have garbage in them, etc. etc.&#10;  So, implementing this would mean that we'd save less data, take longer doing it, and take much longer restoring it.&#10;  The other facet to consider is that this would take a large amount of engineering effort to get it all right. While that's not your problem on the surface, consider that it means that other features you may want to see wouldn't get built.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:44:39.127" EntityChunks="one" Id="148" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T18:11:25.210" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T18:11:25.210" LastEditorUserId="1" NounPhrases="support   bug report info          lot interest,detail,scene,function    type index page segreg separ alloc unit,other mix data page,current look,alloc bitmap,interpret store alloc unit,linear scan data file copi data,file,interpret data structur,slow backup  restor,even interest,lot structur,otherwis,alloc map point page,garbag,etc  etc     implement,less data,much longer restor,facet consid,larg amount engin effort,consid,featur" OwnerUserId="32" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="go,happen,would,mean,implement,see,would,go,interpret,would,skip,interpret,would,drastic,get,would,ba,fix,would,mean,save,take,take,would,take,get,surfac,may,want,see,get,build" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If you switch over to full recovery mode, you can do this with filegroups, but it's really, really clumsy.  You leave the data in the primary filegroup, and put the indexes in a separate (non-default, that's the key) filegroup.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Then you stagger your backups so that you're doing filegroup backups of the primary every night, and transaction log backups every X minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;When disaster strikes, you restore the primary filegroup by itself.  The data is suddenly online, but the indexes are not.  However, to get back to normalcy, you'll need to export that data into a new clean database and add indexes from there.  You can't bring the database completely online without restoring all of the filegroups, and you can't say &quot;I don't need that other filegroup anymore anyway.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;For more about how this works, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://sqlserverpedia.com/wiki/Filegroup_Restore_Script&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;video tutorial on filegroup restores.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T12:06:00.580" EntityChunks="night" Id="509" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T12:06:00.580" NounPhrases="full recoveri mode,realli,realli,clumsi   leav data primari filegroup,index separ,transact,backup everi x minut     disast strike,primari filegroup   data suddenli onlin,normalci,export data,new clean databas,index,databas complet onlin,restor filegroup,filegroup anymor,work  check,video tutori filegroup restor" OwnerUserId="431" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="14" Verbs="switch,data,put,log,suddenli,get,need,add,bring,say,need" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Honestly, you really don't want to do this, even if you overcome the other issues others raise here.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;When you restore the backup in an emergency, you don't want to wait for the indexes to rebuild, and you're going to suffer abominable performance until you do.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I can't think of a situation where you'd want to restore a backup without indexes, so in all cases you'll really want to back them up at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;You'll likely need to look for other solutions to this problem...&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;-Adam&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T17:16:16.403" EntityChunks="" Id="1323" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T17:16:16.403" NounPhrases="realli,index,situat,restor backup,index,case realli,time" OwnerUserId="706" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="5" Verbs="overcom,want,wait,rebuild,go,suffer,perform,think,want,need,adam" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;might be a crazy idea, but here goes.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;ol&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;drop your non-clustered  indexes that take up lots of space&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;do a backup &lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;re-create the indexes you dropped&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ol&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Of course you can only really do this if you database allows for some down-time in the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Also, dont drop your clustered indexes as SQL Server will waste a lot of time converting these to a heap.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Does buying that extra disk space seem like an easier solution yet?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Have you considered doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb964719.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;compressed backups&lt;/a&gt;?  this is a new feature of 2008, it may be an option for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2009-05-04T03:49:27.947" EntityChunks="day" Id="3815" LastActivityDate="2009-05-10T15:22:39.707" LastEditDate="2009-05-10T15:22:39.707" LastEditorUserId="1715" NounPhrases="idea,goe       drop,cluster,lot space   backup    creat index drop,cours realli,databas,cluster index sql,wast lot time,heap,easier solut,consid,new featur" OwnerUserId="1715" ParentId="1" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="may,goe,take,creat,allow,do,drop,buy,seem,compress,may,option" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I've used &lt;a href=&quot;http://gparted.sourceforge.net/livecd.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;GParted Live CD&lt;/a&gt; in the past with success, it's a linux boot disk designed for partitoning.  I should have mentioned that despite being a linux disk, it works for sorting out windows partitions too.  I split my laptop up to install the windows 7 beta using this.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:31.473" EntityChunks="" Id="34" LastActivityDate="2009-05-02T10:13:12.860" LastEditDate="2009-05-02T10:13:12.860" LastEditorUserId="38" NounPhrases=" use,live cd,success,boot disk design partiton,mention,despit linux disk,sort window partit,split laptop instal window,beta" OwnerUserId="38" ParentId="23" PostTypeId="2" Score="17" Verbs="gpart" />
  <row Body="&lt;ol&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;As far as windows is concerned, before the 1st service pack is almost always buggy&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ol&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;pretty much in that order&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:30.340" EntityChunks="" Id="28" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:07:30.340" NounPhrases="   price   far window concern,st servic pack,much order" OwnerUserId="38" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="pretti" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm usually keen to upgrade to the latest versions of an OS, however the most common reasons I have found for people not want to upgrade is either the compatability of old software, or not wanting to learn a new OS.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:52.820" EntityChunks="" Id="29" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:07:52.820" NounPhrases=" usual keen upgrad latest version,common reason,peopl,either compat old softwar" OwnerUserId="48" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="howev,find,want,want,learn" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The current one just works!&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:18.447" EntityChunks="one" Id="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:09:18.447" NounPhrases=" current one work" OwnerUserId="53" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="26" Verbs="" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The hassle of reinstalling all my applications is the #1 reason for me. That and the fact that even after I reinstall, there'll most probably be incompatibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:48.523" EntityChunks="" Id="36" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:09:48.523" NounPhrases=" hassl reinstal applic    reason,fact,even reinstal  probabl incompat" OwnerUserId="35" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Upgrading the OS on a server that is hosting lots of websites means many many hours reinstalling the sites on the new server, not to mention the downtime and the ever-present risk of missing some undocumented third-party component or service installed on the old server.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Same is true on a personal computer (though more of the work goes into reinstalling applications, and reconfiguring the environment).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;If it ain't broke, don't fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:10:01.520" EntityChunks="hour,third" Id="39" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:10:01.520" NounPhrases="server host lot,mani mani hour reinstal site new server,downtim,undocu third parti,servic instal old server,true person" OwnerUserId="34" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="mean,miss,goe,break,fix" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I always format / install. NEVER upgrade. Keep it nice and clean. too many places crap can get lost or dup'd.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;But if u mean going from older version to a new version, it's generally &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;ol&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Having to re-install everything again.&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ol&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;edit: This is referring to Windows OS, not linux, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:14:03.397" EntityChunks="" Id="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T23:53:33.997" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T23:53:33.997" LastEditorUserId="58" NounPhrases="nice clean  mani place crap,dup,older version new version,gener       price   instal everyth       edit,window" OwnerUserId="58" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="22" Verbs="keep,get,lose,mean,go,refer" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In a lot of cases, the compatibility of important software is not known. It may be even worse if the software was not updated since some time.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:15:49.243" EntityChunks="" Id="51" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:15:49.243" NounPhrases=" lot case,compat import softwar,softwar updat sinc time" OwnerUserId="84" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="know,may,softwar" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;For me, it has to be downtime &amp;amp; loss of productivity.  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;On the desktop front, even though I try and keep my system relatively &quot;clean&quot; in terms of what is installed, it is still set up exactly how I need it.  In the past, I've found it takes 2 or 3 days per year's worth of data / applications / settings to migrate to a clean OS install: with data being the most time consuming - checking out scores of projects from a half dozen different SVN repositories just isn't a quick process.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;On the server front, &quot;upgrade&quot; is a bit of a misnomer: I would never ever upgrade the entire OS of a server whilst it was &quot;live&quot;: critical patches would be as far as I went (if it ain't broke, don't fix it).  When choosing a new server, it really depends on the requirements, but others have said, it's not really worth the hassle of being on the crest of the wave with a new OS - let others who can afford to throw money at problems trial and error it.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:02.713" EntityChunks="half dozen" Id="65" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:02.713" NounPhrases="  downtim,amp,loss product,desktop,front,tri,system,term,exactli need,year,data   applic   set migrat,instal  data time,check score project,half dozen differ svn,quick process,server front,bit misnom,entir,server,live   critic patch,choos new server,depend requir,other afford,money problem trial error" OwnerUserId="40" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="keep,set,find,take,consum,repositori,would,live,would,go,break,fix,choo,depend,say,let,throw" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I subscribe to the &quot;If it ain't broke&quot; policy, especially on server versions.  Having to go through the pain of working out how to get everything up and working in the new version tends to keep me with the version I currently have.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Only when the new features become essential and required do I feel the need to go through the process again.  And then only when the new essential features outweigh the process of working out how to get everything working again.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:30:03.470" EntityChunks="" Id="98" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:30:03.470" NounPhrases=" subscrib,polici,server version,pain work,everyth,new version,version,current     new featur becom essenti requir,process   new essenti featur outweigh process work,everyth work" OwnerUserId="115" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="break,go,get,work,tend,keep,feel,nee,go,process,get" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think it depends on the frequency the software is upgraded. If a new version comes out every 3-6 months, I would be upgrading systems almost everyday.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:38:14.697" EntityChunks="" Id="129" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:38:14.697" NounPhrases="new version,everi     month,system" OwnerUserId="132" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="think,depend,come,would,upgrad" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Having a large estate of computers which all need to be upgraded together. Having multiple Operating Systems or versions of operating systems complicates support.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Having to migrate lots of machines at once is also more complicated and requires more app compatibility checking beforehand and user support after.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:43:45.277" EntityChunks="" Id="147" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:43:45.277" NounPhrases="estat comput need,multipl oper system version oper system complic support     migrat lot machin,requir app compat check,beforehand user support" OwnerUserId="156" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="larg" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;One Lession that I learned the hard way many times, I treat it as a law: You can NOT upgrade Windows. Formatting/Reinstalling is faster than &quot;upgrading&quot; and dealing with the issues. I've got bitten by this so often, even with seemingly straight-forward upgrades like Win2000 =&gt; WinXP.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The other reason is the &quot;Never touch a running system&quot; rule. If it runs &lt;em&gt;and there are no security vulnerabilities impacting it&lt;/em&gt;, don't touch it.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:46:26.330" EntityChunks="one" Id="153" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:46:26.330" NounPhrases=" one lession,hard way,law,window,issu,win        winxp     reason,run system,rule,run,vulner impact   touch" OwnerUserId="151" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="learn,format,get,bite,seemingli,touch,secur" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I use Linux at work (Ubuntu 8.10) and I am very wary of updates around the kernel / driver area or updating to new versions (i.e. 9.04) because:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;It currently works&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;I can't afford to not be productive for a day+ while I reinstall my OS&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;At home it's a different story because that's &lt;em&gt;my time&lt;/em&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:09:18.460" EntityChunks="day" Id="202" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:09:18.460" NounPhrases="linux work,kernel   driver area,updat new version,time" OwnerUserId="183" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="use" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I used to be the kind of guy who would jump to the latest OS as soon as it was out of beta. But with the shift from XP to Vista, I have become more cautious and conservative. You've all heard the horror stories about simple things that broke. For me it was the ability to connect to my company's VPN and use remote desktop to get to my work machine, which incidentally, I still can't get going.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;That experience, coupled with the advances we've seen in virtualization recently (which makes trying an OS before you commit much more practical), means I'll be much slower on the uptake of Windows 7.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Short answer: I got burnt. Pain is an excellent teacher.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:15:19.647" EntityChunks="" Id="212" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:15:19.647" NounPhrases="kind guy,xp,vista,becom,cautiou conserv,horror stori simpl thing,connect,work,incident,experi,tri,much slower uptak window,short answer,pain excel teacher" OwnerUserId="195" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="2" Verbs="use,would,jump,shift,hear,break,get,get,go,see,make,commit,mean,get,burn,excel" />
  <row Body="&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Inefficiency of the new operating&#10;system (e.g. Vista)&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Speed of performing common tasks&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;No new features which I really like.&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:27:22.020" EntityChunks="" Id="233" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:27:22.020" NounPhrases="   ineffici,new oper system,e g  vista    speed,common task   new featur realli" OwnerUserId="235" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="perform" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Stability.  We know the applications work on the OS they're running on, and any change to the environment can introduce unintended consequences.  Usually the OS is updated at the same time we're planning to deploy new hardware.  We can purchase the hardware, configure the OS, install the software and test, test, then test some more before deploying to the production environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T14:28:21.627" EntityChunks="" Id="884" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T14:28:21.627" NounPhrases=" stabil,applic work,chang environ introduc unintend consequ,usual os updat time plan,new hardwar   purchas hardwar,configur,instal softwar test,test,test,product environ" OwnerUserId="671" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="know,deploy" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Time involvement and stability, whether talking about Linux or Windows.  With Windows, I haven't tried an upgrade in a long time, but experience has taught me to avoid the first release of any Windows OS.  I always wait until SP1 comes out, unless I hear otherwise from friends who are early adopters.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;With Linux, I've always used Red Hat.  With Fedora, Red Hat releases have become more bleeding edge than they used to be.  Due to this, I don't rush to upgrade my Fedora machines.  I wait until a release has been out at least a few weeks and I read reviews from early adopters.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I have no experience with Mac (regarding installation and upgrades), but with Windows and with Linux, I find new releases are often not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; ready for prime time.  I know if I used a less bleeding edge Linux distribution (such as Debian) then it would probably be more safe to upgrade as soon as a release comes out, but I'm a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2009/04/no-we-have-not-forgotten-about-the-hacker-badge/&quot;&gt;hacker&lt;/a&gt; from way back, and I like solving problems.  (That's one reason I'm on SO and SF!)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Above I talked about the stability aspect.  For any OS, it's often easier to reinstall rather than upgrade.  For Linux, I'll often upgrade once or twice (a year apart) and then do a complete reinstall in place of the next upgrade.  For Windows, I normally just replace the hardware and install a new OS on the new hardware.  Why ever reinstall Linux? Well, as open source advances, some packages are replaced or discarded.  When you upgrade, bits of flotsam are left behind, some in &lt;code&gt;/etc&lt;/code&gt; and some in &lt;code&gt;/var&lt;/code&gt; and some in other places.  On a re-install, all of that cruft is cleaned away.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;That's the time involvement.  Doing an upgrade takes time to clean up cruft (in Linux, *.rpmnew and *.rpmsave, for example).  A full reinstall takes time, of course, to ensure that nothing is lost, everything is reconfigured and reinstalled, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="1" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-01T02:28:31.410" EntityChunks="first,one" Id="2039" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T02:28:31.410" NounPhrases=" time involv stabil,first releas window,otherwis friend,red hat   fedora,red hat releas becom,rush upgrad fedora machin,wait releas,review,earli adopt     experi mac,instal upgrad   window linux,new releas,readi,less bleed edg linux distribut,releas,solv problem,one reason,talk stabil aspect,linux,reinstal place,upgrad   window,new hardwar,ever reinstal linux,open sourc advanc,packag replac discard,bit flotsam,clean away     time,time,clean cruft,linux,rpmnew   rpmsave,full reinstal take time,cours,ensur,everyth,reconfigur reinstal" OwnerUserId="808" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="teach,wait,come,hear,adopt,use,bleed,use,adopt,regard,find,quit,know,use,bleed,would,probabl,come,leave,place,clean,take,exampl,lose" />
  <row Body="&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Current one is still supported by the vendor&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;New one does not work with current software (and I can't get a replacement for the current software)&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;New one does not work with current hardware (and I have no budget to upgrade/replace hardware)&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;The company I work for has not yet tested the OS from a functional and security perspective&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-25T19:08:37.027" EntityChunks="one" Id="12055" LastActivityDate="2009-05-25T19:08:37.027" NounPhrases="vendor,new one work,current softwar,replac,current softwar,new one work,current hardwar,budget,upgrad replac hardwar,compani work,function secur perspect" OwnerUserId="137" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="support,get,secur" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;If not USB support - i'd still be runing windows NT 4 sp6.&#10;But since I moved to 2000 I jump on every new client os as soon as it gets out, just to see where MS are going with it. And only tonns of stored data can stop me for awhile, but not for too long.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-25T21:28:49.133" EntityChunks="" Id="12085" LastActivityDate="2009-05-25T21:28:49.133" NounPhrases=" usb support,window,nt   sp   sinc move,jump,new client,ms,awhil" OwnerUserId="2620" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="rune,get,see,go,stop" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;There are usually enough things I hate about the current version that are fixed in the next one that I end up upgrading sooner rather than later. I was on Vista x64 a year after it was out, and everything worked absolutely fine - which was quite unexpected given all the bad reputation it had.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2012-10-21T16:06:40.293" EntityChunks="one" Id="440710" LastActivityDate="2012-10-21T16:06:40.293" NounPhrases=" noth     usual enough thing,next one end,vista,work absolut fine   quit unexpect,bad reput" OwnerUserId="14642" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="hate,give" />
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;(Sorry for the rant, ignore it if you wish, I just &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to write this somewhere.)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Windows 8 is just plain ugly and unusable on a desktop system.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Windows Server 2012 is even worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know, lots of technical improvements and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;But the UI totally sucks, and that's a death blow for Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2012-10-21T16:19:42.710" EntityChunks="" Id="440712" LastActivityDate="2012-10-21T16:19:42.710" NounPhrases="somewher        window   plain ugli unus desktop system     window server,even wors,ye,lot technic improv     ui total suck,death blow microsoft" OwnerUserId="6352" ParentId="21" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="wish,write,know,ui" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;There are no problems with running multiple sites from the same folder, I have done it many times. The advantage you gain by running separate sites in separate app pools is resilience to crashes, if an error is caused in one site, it is less likely to affect the others. It also means that if one site is more popular than the others you can alter the pool settings to make that more efficient when recycling threads if required.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:04:56.337" EntityChunks="one,one" Id="20" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:04:56.337" NounPhrases=" problem,multipl site folder,advantag gain,separ site separ app pool resili crash,error caus,one site,one site popular other alter pool" OwnerUserId="48" ParentId="16" PostTypeId="2" Score="6" Verbs="run,do,run,affect,mean,set,make" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;No reason to use multiple app pools unless you have an explicit reason for separating them. Otherwise it's just waste of memory.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;There shouldn't be any issues in running multiple websites off the same directory. If at some point a client needs a different version, you can migrate them onto a different dir with a specialized code base / config / etc. If this is a scenario that might occur more often, then you might consider separating them onto different websites up front.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:05:22.170" EntityChunks="" Id="22" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:05:22.170" NounPhrases=" reason,multipl app pool,explicit reason separ,wast memori     issu,multipl websit directori,point,differ,version,differ dir special code base   config,scenario,separ,differ websit" OwnerUserId="24" ParentId="16" PostTypeId="2" Score="8" Verbs="otherwis,run,nee,may,occur,may,consid" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been running soft raid5 on Ubuntu since 6.10, and always upgraded without problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Note that in Jaunty (9.04), which is not LTS, there's a bug where degraded arrays don't start automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:44:55.477" EntityChunks="" Id="152" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:44:55.477" NounPhrases="soft raid,problem     note jaunti,bug degrad array,start" OwnerUserId="28" ParentId="15" PostTypeId="2" Score="2" Verbs="run" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;First off, 7.10 and 8.10 are not LTS (long term support) release. The only LTS releases so far are 6.06 and 8.04.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, 7.10 is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/news/ubuntu-7.10-eol&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;no longer supported&lt;/a&gt; - that means that you will no longer receive security updates (or any other updates). So you should definitely upgrade to the 8.04 LTS release (known as the Hardy Heron).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;To do so (assuming you don't have a desktop environment installed) then install update-manager-core if it is not already installed:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install update-manager-core&#10;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Launch the upgrade tool&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo do-release-upgrade&#10;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Follow the on-screen instructions. (Instructions from &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/HardyUpgrades&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T13:50:04.667" EntityChunks="" Id="805" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T14:38:56.857" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T14:38:56.857" LastEditorUserId="629" NounPhrases=" first            lt  long term support,definit,lt releas,hardi heron       assum desktop environ instal  instal updat manag core alreadi,sudo,instal updat manag core,launch upgrad tool     sudo,follow screen" OwnerUserId="629" ParentId="15" PostTypeId="2" Score="7" Verbs="lt,lt,support,mean,receiv,secur,lt,know,heron,get,launch,releas,follow" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Have just found out what the problem was (well, my hosting provider did). Changed code by adding '%COMSPEC% /C' (where %COMSPEC% holds the path to cmd.exe) to the front of the command.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dim cmd : cmd = &quot;%COMSPEC% /C sqlcmd -S &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_SERVER &amp;amp; &quot; -U &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_UID &amp;amp; &quot; -P &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_PWD &amp;amp; &quot; -d &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_NAME &amp;amp; &quot; -i &quot;&quot;&quot; &amp;amp; scriptPath &amp;amp; &quot;&quot;&quot; -b&quot;&#10;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;It now works just dandy. I'm not sure about the whys/hows so I'll leave the question unanswered for now for someone to answer more comprehensively if they can.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T11:16:26.097" EntityChunks="" Id="394" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T11:16:26.097" NounPhrases="problem,comspec,path cmd,front command,cmd   cmd     comspec   c sqlcmd     amp,databas server,amp,amp,amp,databas pwd,amp,amp,databas name,amp,amp,scriptpath,amp,b       work,leav,someon answer comprehens" OwnerUserId="39" ParentId="12" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="find,provid,hold,cmd,whi,question" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozy.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Mozy&lt;/a&gt; on both OSX (primarly) and Windows for over a year now with few problems, including during testing of recovery. The biggest problem, which I don't think is solved by any backup solution, is the slowing of the computer caused by encoding or determining which files need to be backed up. Also, Mozy is very cheap and they have both enterprise (reasonable pricing) and personal backup solutions (especially cheap) There are other similar services out there now.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Another service that seems quite similar is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Blackblaze&lt;/a&gt;. Similar pricing and services to that of Mozy.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:55.450" EntityChunks="" Id="38" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T18:45:07.273" LastEditDate="2009-05-01T18:45:07.273" LastEditorUserId="25" NounPhrases=" use,mozi,osx,primarli,window year problem,includ test recoveri,biggest problem,solv backup solut,comput caus,determin file,mozi cheap enterpris,reason price,person backup solut,cheap  similar servic     anoth servic,similar price servic mozi" OwnerUserId="25" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="think,need,especi,seem,quit,blackblaz" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The only multi-machine mixed Mac OS X and Windows backup system I've used is Dantz Retrospect; Dantz was bought by EMC several years back, and Retrospect is still a living product.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;My experience back in the late 1990s through early 2000s was that they provided a great incremental backup tool for multiple systems on a LAN.  It did take them a release to shake out their Windows and Mac OS X support but once they did, I started hearing good things about their Windows backup solutions too.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Back in the early 2000s their Windows and Windows Server (including Exchange) backup support was good enough that it resulted in a department of a Very Large Company that I was doing some consulting for to switch to Retrospect.  I was doing software development for them, not systems/network administration; it was the Windows people at their site who discovered and dove into Retrospect.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:21:55.360" EntityChunks="" Id="72" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:21:55.360" NounPhrases=" multi machin mix mac,window backup system,dantz retrospect,bought emc sever year back  retrospect,product     experi,great increment backup tool,releas,window mac,support,earli     window window,includ,exchang,backup support,larg compani consult,retrospect,softwar,system network administr,window peopl site discov,retrospect" OwnerUserId="91" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="use,buy,live,provid,shake,start,hear" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Windows Home Serer supports Backup of 10 PCs, so it's perfect for a Windows Office.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;And didn't the last update add TimeMachine support for Mac?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:11:28.720" EntityChunks="" Id="205" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:11:28.720" NounPhrases=" window home serer support backup,last updat,timemachin support mac" OwnerUserId="209" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="add" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I used to use Mozy. but these days I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;BackBlaze&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I found Mozy to be pretty flakey, and it used to hog my CPU a lot.  I've found Backblaze to be competitive and less intrusive.  In the end you need to give both solutions a try to find out which one works for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T14:09:12.653" EntityChunks="" Id="840" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T14:09:12.653" NounPhrases="use mozi,day use,mozi pretti flakey,hog,cpu lot,less intrus,solut,tri,one work" OwnerUserId="197" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="use,find,use,find,nee,give,find" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Since you mentioned enterprise backup, I'll mention both Tivoli Storage Manager and Veritas NetBackup. Tivoli tends to be more IBM-centric whereas NetBackup pretty much has clients for just about everything.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;NetBackup is painful to configure but once you get it working, it'll keep on going. I've implemented a system for a customer that was backing up over 48TB daily with over a 99+% success rate.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I have no idea about smaller systems =)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-01T06:01:02.757" EntityChunks="" Id="2187" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T06:01:02.757" NounPhrases=" sinc mention,tivoli storag manag verita netbackup,tivoli,centric wherea netbackup,much client everyth     netbackup pain configur,work,system custom,tb daili      success rate     idea smaller system" OwnerUserId="97" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="mention,tend,ibm,pretti,get,keep,implement" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jungledisk.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Jungledisk&lt;/a&gt; and have been extremely happy with it for data backup purposes, for &lt;em&gt;OS&lt;/em&gt; backup I'm just Time Machine on my Mac and for Windows I'm prepared to reinstall if the worst happens.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syncplicity.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;syncplicity&lt;/a&gt; to keep just my &quot;work files&quot; in sync between work/home/laptop machines.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-01T06:07:31.790" EntityChunks="" Id="2190" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T06:07:31.790" NounPhrases=" use,jungledisk  extrem happi data backup purpos,backup time,machin mac window prepar reinstal worst happen     top,use,syncplic,work file,work home laptop machin" OwnerUserId="1222" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="happi,happen,keep" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crashplan.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;CrashPlan&lt;/a&gt; is terrific.  I use it to back up several Macs and a Windows box to local/network disks and remote servers over the Internet (mine, not theirs).  It easily supports multiple destinations per machine, does incremental backups forever, deduplication, compression, etc.  Also, it'll do near-as-continuous backups (every couple of minutes, if you want) and handles strange network configurations seamlessly, which makes it a great fit for laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Before CrashPlan I used a combination of Retrospect and Bacula.  I really wouldn't recommend either, for different reasons.  Both haven't made the transition from tape to disk backups, so you end up storing big sequential files on disk like tape, and still have to manually manage your backup generations, redo full backups and so forth.  Of the two, Bacula, while a pain to set up, is considerably more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-05-01T08:04:50.853" EntityChunks="two" Id="2233" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T08:04:50.853" NounPhrases="  crashplan,use,easili support,multipl destin,machin,backup forev,dedupl,compress,handl strang network configur seamlessli,retrospect bacula,reason,end,store,big sequenti file disk,tape,still manual manag backup gener,full backup,pain,reliabl" OwnerUserId="1093" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="7" Verbs="terrif,minut,want,make,recommend,differ,make,redo,set,consider" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I think you want something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ironmountain.com/digital/pc/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; from Iron Mountain.  It is centrally managed and they say they support PCs and Macs.   &lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-01T18:55:20.290" EntityChunks="" Id="2681" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T18:55:20.290" NounPhrases="iron mountain   central manag" OwnerUserId="846" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="think,want,say" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Unitrends has a great system for backing up your business computers/servers. They support most OSs. Master backups and BareMetal restores to dissimilar hardware in case something happens to your location.  Might be a bit pricey at first glance, but there customer support is amazing and the system just works.  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2010-09-02T19:27:12.807" EntityChunks="first" Id="177468" LastActivityDate="2010-09-02T19:27:12.807" NounPhrases="great system,busi comput server,oss,master,backup baremet restor dissimilar hardwar case,locat" OwnerDisplayName="jrm" ParentId="10" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="unitrend,happen,may,pricey" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;In the past I have used Symantec Corporate Edition quite extensively. Whilst their Norton products have a bad rap (for good reason) for being slow, the corporate version was pretty quick and unobtrusive and had a good managment console. However that was a few years ago so they could have ruined it by now.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I've recently had to use kaspersky and I don't recommend it from what I saw. It may have been the version I was given but the centralised management features were a bit of a joke.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:00:06.207" EntityChunks="year ago" Id="13" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:00:06.207" NounPhrases="use,corpor edit,quit,extens,norton product bad rap,good reason,corpor version,quick unobtrus good manag consol,howev,centralis manag featur bit joke" OwnerUserId="48" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="pretti,could,ruin,see,may,version,give" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We use NOD32. The main reason for choosing it was because it was less of a resource-hog than the others.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:01:14.240" EntityChunks="" Id="17" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:01:14.240" NounPhrases="nod" OwnerUserId="35" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="15" Verbs="use,choo" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;avast! Professional Edition has some nice features like creating a preconfigured installation, background scanning (doesn't hog the hard drive while the computer is under load) and can be configured to be user-friendly in not dropping millions of notifications on him. There are some server products avast! authors offer, like avast! Distributed Network Manager.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;At my side IT job I only used the client Professional Edition, without the management server or DNM and it worked very well.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:24:39.613" EntityChunks="million" Id="82" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:24:39.613" NounPhrases=" avast,profession edit nice featur,creat preconfigur,hard drive comput load,friendli,server,product avast,author offer,avast,distribut network manag     side job use,client profession edit,manag server dnm work" OwnerUserId="36" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="edit,hog,drop" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;AVG professional. In my experience AVG does a good job is keeping their definitions up to date and does a thorough job.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;One of the features i quite like about the site editions is the push functionality, it works quite well as long as there isn't a firewall in its way and easy to keep organized.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:42:32.317" EntityChunks="one" Id="142" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:42:32.317" NounPhrases="profession,good job,date,site edit push function,quit,well long firewal way easi,organ" OwnerUserId="123" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="avg,avg,keep,quit,keep" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We use McAfee and I would warn you from using it. It is veeeery slow. Previously we had AVG and it was much faster.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Edit:&#10;Oh, and it has deleted my 'bluescreen' screensaver from sysinternals. One day it popped up the window saying a virus with category 'joke' will be deleted. No options to ignore and keep it...&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:55:50.550" EntityChunks="one day" Id="175" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:22:13.857" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T09:22:13.857" LastEditorUserId="184" NounPhrases="mcafe,use,edit,oh  delet,sysintern  one day pop window,viru categori,delet" OwnerUserId="184" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="5" Verbs="use,would,warn,avg,say,keep" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We use the kaspersky corporate anti-virus suite and love it!&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:05:43.197" EntityChunks="" Id="191" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:05:43.197" NounPhrases="kasperski corpor" OwnerUserId="66" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="use,love" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I can say one that &lt;strong&gt;it's not&lt;/strong&gt;: CA eTrust.&#10;It's a pure resource vampire and never convinced me at its effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:10:56.070" EntityChunks="" Id="204" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:10:56.070" NounPhrases="effect" OwnerUserId="132" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="say,ca,etrust,convinc" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;We have stopped recommending strict anti-virus software, and have moved to anti-malware at this point.  Centrally controlled/distributed is a must.  I agree with some of the people here that McAfee and Symantec have just gotten out of control with their bloatware.  We have found a lot of success with F-Secure.  It has a nice interface, not too heavy, the centralized management is pretty good.  It covers viruses, spyware, internet usage, email, etc.  Their support has been good so far and deployment has been pretty straightforward.  We have it setup on a few networks.  Since you are going to need something that works for your environment, I suggest you setup some virtual environments and test each of your candidates out, especially on the user experience side, I would guess you want the least intrusive software to minimize desktop support questions.  Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T11:51:09.290" EntityChunks="" Id="472" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T11:51:09.290" NounPhrases="strict anti viru softwar,anti malwar point   central control distribut,must   agre peopl mcafe symantec,control,lot success,nice interfac,heavi,central manag,good   cover virus,internet,email,etc   support,pretti straightforward   setup network   sinc,especi,user experi side,least intrus softwar minim desktop support question,good luck" OwnerUserId="340" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="stop,recommend,move,must,get,find,secur,pretti,deploy,go,need,suggest,would,guess,want" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I always use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.malwarebytes.org/products/malwarebytes_free&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Malwarebytes&lt;/a&gt; for spot removal since it just seems to remove what Symantec often can't - has anyone tried the pro version?  The site doesn't list any centralized management features...&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2012-08-06T20:06:15.843" EntityChunks="" Id="414825" LastActivityDate="2012-08-06T20:06:15.843" NounPhrases=" alway use,spot remov sinc,anyon,central manag featur" OwnerUserId="103189" ParentId="7" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="list" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The primary reason is performance. When you run out of IOPS capacity on your primary filegroup disk drive, you'll need to expand onto a second filegroup to split IOPS over multiple disks/LUNs depending on storage config.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;EDIT:&#10;Brad Wilson made a good comment regarding SSDs. If you're using a composite SSD/SATA/FC storage system, you may want to have different filegroups on different types of storage. You can then put your extreme IOPS requirement tables onto SSD filegropus, while history/stats tables may be stored on cheap SATA filegroups.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:58:55.523" EntityChunks="second" Id="11" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:17:01.860" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:17:01.860" LastEditorUserId="24" NounPhrases=" primari reason,iop capac primari filegroup disk drive,second filegroup split,iop multipl disk lun,depend storag config     edit,brad,wilson,good comment regard,use,composit ssd sata,storag system,differ filegroup differ type storag,extrem iop requir tabl,ssd filegropu,stat tabl,cheap sata filegroup" OwnerUserId="24" ParentId="6" PostTypeId="2" Score="6" Verbs="run,nee,expand,depend,make,composit,may,want,differ,put,may,store" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;There's two parts to this question: when to add a new FILEGROUP, and when to add a new FILE in a filegroup.  First let's talk theory:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Mark's right about the primary reason being performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The secondary reason is disaster recovery.  With SQL Server 2005 and newer, you can do filegroup restores.  When disaster strikes, you can restore just your primary filegroup first and bring the database partially online for queries.  Users can run queries while you're restoring other filegroups.  This is useful for databases with a large amount of historical data that may not be required right away, or data warehouses that need to load data into current tables without needing historical data for access.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Another reason is the read/write profile of groups of data.  If you have some data that is constantly written to, and other data that gets heavy read activity, you can build different types of storage to accommodate those needs.  You could put the heavy-write stuff on raid 10, and leave the read-biased stuff on cheaper raid 5.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Now, let's talk files versus filegroups.  When you place objects in SQL Server, you have to place them at the filegroup level.  You can land a table or an index in a filegroup, but you can't pick a specific file.  So everything we've discussed so far has been about when to add a filegroup - but when do you add a file?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;If you're designing storage, and you have 80 hard drives, there's a few ways you can break it up:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;One pool of 80 drives&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Two pools of 40 drives&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;Four pools of 20 drives, etc...&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Different storage subsystems have different performance profiles.  I've worked with some SANs that performed best with 12-16 drive arrays, and anything larger than that didn't have a performance improvement.  Another example is SANs with multipathing: if you have several HBAs connecting your server to your storage, and if your multipathing software isn't real active/active, then you may need one array per path in order to distribute load.  Four paths, four pools of drives will get better performance on those types of drives.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;In those cases, you end up with four different arrays, four different drives under Windows (unless you use mount points, and even then it's different folders) and you'll need four separate files in SQL Server.  Those separate files can be in the same filegroup.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T12:16:18.353" EntityChunks="two,first,one,two,four,one,four,four,four,four,four" Id="537" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T12:16:18.353" NounPhrases=" two part question,new filegroup,new file filegroup,talk theori     mark right primari reason,secondari reason,sql server,filegroup restor   disast strike,primari filegroup,partial onlin,user,queri restor filegroup,use,databas larg amount histor data,data warehous need load data,current tabl,need,histor data access     anoth reason,profil group data   data constantli,data,heavi,activ,differ type storag accommod,heavi,stuff raid,leav,bias stuff,cheaper raid,talk,versu filegroup,sql server,filegroup level   land tabl index filegroup,specif file   everyth,filegroup,file     design storag     hard drive,storag subsystem,work,drive array,larger perform,improv   anoth exampl san multipath,hba connect server storag,multipath softwar real activ activ,one array,path order distribut load,four path,four pool drive,type drive     case,four differ array,four differ drive window,mount point,folder,four separ file sql server   separ file filegroup" OwnerUserId="431" ParentId="6" PostTypeId="2" Score="19" Verbs="add,add,let,talk,perform,bring,run,may,requir,need,read,write,write,get,read,build,need,could,put,write,read,let,place,pick,discuss,add,add,break,drive,drive,differ,differ,profil,perform,improv,exampl,may,need,get,perform,end,differ,need" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I would also point out there is a recoverabiltiy / data availability aspect to this question as well. By using multiple file groups, and not placing any user defined objects on the primary file group, you have more flexibility in enabling online restores. this allows piecemeal restore at the file group level.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Online restore are available in Enterprise and Developer editions of sql server later than 2005&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Another thought that comes to mind is to separate read only static reference data from transactional data. For larger databases, this could reduce the amount of time and /or space needed to perform a backup.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-07-08T07:23:49.527" EntityChunks="" Id="37536" LastActivityDate="2009-07-08T07:23:49.527" NounPhrases="recoverabiltiy   data avail aspect question,multipl file group,user defin object primari file group,enabl onlin restor,piecem restor file group level     onlin restor avail enterpris,edit sql server,mind separ,static refer data transact data  larger databas,amount time,backup" OwnerUserId="3236" ParentId="6" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="would,point,use,flexibl,allow,develop,think,come,read,could,reduc,need,perform" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Regarding your third question: I always run a local repository. Even if it's only for one machine, it saves time in case I need to reinstall (I generally use something like aptitude autoclean), and for two machines, it almost always pays off.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;For the clusters I admin, I don't generally keep explicit logs: I let the package manager do it for me. However, for those machines (as opposed to desktops), I don't use automatic installations, so I do have my notes about what I intended to install to all machines.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:49:58.027" EntityChunks="third,two" Id="4" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T07:49:58.027" NounPhrases="third question,alway run local repositori,even one machin,time case,reinstal  gener use,aptitud,two machin,pay     cluster admin,gener,explicit log,packag manag,oppos desktop   use automat,note,intend instal machin" OwnerUserId="28" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="10" Verbs="regard,run,save,need,pay,keep,let,intend" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You can have a local repository and configure all servers to point to it for updates. Not only you get speed of local downloads, you also get to control which official updates you want installed on your infrastructure in order to prevent any compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;On the Windows side of things, I've used &lt;a href=&quot;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/wsus/default.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Windows Server Update Services&lt;/a&gt; with very satisfying results.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:57:15.653" EntityChunks="" Id="8" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T07:57:15.653" NounPhrases=" local repositori configur server point updat,speed local download,control offici updat,instal infrastructur order,compat issu     window side thing" OwnerUserId="36" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="repositori,get,get,want,result" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;On Linux/Debian based systems, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/search?keywords=cron-apt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;cron-apt&lt;/a&gt; is a very handy tool that can manage automating apt via cron.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I'm using it to &lt;code&gt;apt-get update&lt;/code&gt; every day and send me an email if new updates has to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian-administration.org/articles/162&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;short and well-done introduction on that tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="1" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:31:33.760" EntityChunks="" Id="104" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:31:33.760" NounPhrases="debian base system,cron,apt  handi tool manag autom,cron     use   everi day,email,introduct tool" OwnerUserId="117" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="19" Verbs="linux,use,send,do" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://freshmeat.net/projects/apt-history/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;apt-history&lt;/a&gt; for history. I've no idea why this useful tool isn't included by default, it's the first package I deploy with &lt;a href=&quot;http://reductivelabs.com/products/puppet/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;puppet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T14:45:57.403" EntityChunks="" Id="930" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T14:45:57.403" NounPhrases="histori,idea use tool includ default,first packag deploy" OwnerUserId="677" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="use" />
  <row Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;When using a package manager like&#10;  Aptitude, do you keep an upgrade /&#10;  install history, and if so, how do you&#10;  do it?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;apt keeps a log in /var/log/apt/, and dpkg uses /var/log/dpkg.log. dpkg in particular is fairly parsable. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-01T21:04:48.903" EntityChunks="" Id="2791" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T21:04:48.903" NounPhrases="packag manag,aptitud,var log apt   dpkg use,var log dpkg log,dpkg,particular fairli parsabl" OwnerUserId="919" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="use,keep,keep" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I run &lt;strong&gt;/usr/bin/apt-get update -qq;/usr/bin/apt-get dist-upgrade -duyq&lt;/strong&gt; as a cron job every night.  In the morning I have notification of what packages need to be upgraded, and the files have already been downloaded on the machine.  &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Then I typically take a snapshot of the machine (most of our servers are virtual), do an &lt;strong&gt;apt-get dist-upgrade&lt;/strong&gt;, check &lt;strong&gt;nagios&lt;/strong&gt; and ensure everything is still working, and remove the snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I keep a running list of all changes made to every server on a &lt;strong&gt;wiki&lt;/strong&gt;, in order to track any problems that arise later.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;As far as limiting redundant downloads, I understand that you can set up a &lt;strong&gt;cacheing web-proxy&lt;/strong&gt; (squid?) between your servers and the internet that will cache the .deb files the first time they are accessed.  Perhaps this is simpler than setting up a local package repository - and has the added benefit of speeding up general web browsing.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-01T21:31:57.497" EntityChunks="first" Id="2810" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T21:40:23.887" LastEditDate="2009-05-01T21:40:23.887" LastEditorUserId="1466" NounPhrases="usr bin,qq  usr,bin,duyq,notif packag need,file alreadi download machin       typic,snapshot machin,server,check,nagio,ensur everyth,run list chang,far limit redund download,deb file,first time access,perhap simpler" OwnerUserId="1466" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="3" Verbs="run,get,get,take,get,work,remov,keep,make,limit,understand,set,set,repositori,brow" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;apt-cacher is handy for caching packages, it'll cache the first time they're needed rather than completing a full mirror of the entire repository thus saving disk and bandwidth.  It's also handy as it streams the first request of a package direct to the requester while caching it at the same time so there's no additional delay.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-02T23:29:29.093" EntityChunks="first,first" Id="3344" LastActivityDate="2009-05-02T23:29:29.093" NounPhrases="cach packag,full mirror entir,thu save disk bandwidth,stream first request packag direct request,time addit delay" OwnerUserId="914" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="handi,nee,complet,repositori,save,handi" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Running a local repository is the best way to manage exactly what's on your local servers.  It also lets you easily deploy custom backports or custom local packages.  I've been known to make local 'meta packages' that are just a huge ilst of dependencies to make a local install easy. (eg. 'apt-get install local-mailserver').  This has the side effect of also letting you 'version' your config changes.  (For more complicated config managment you'll need something like Puppet)&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-04T14:47:16.570" EntityChunks="" Id="4049" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T14:47:16.570" NounPhrases="best way manag,local server,custom backport custom local packag,meta packag,huge ilst,local instal easi,instal local mailserv     side effect,config chang,complic config manag,puppet" OwnerUserId="613" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="run,repositori,exactli,let,know,make,depend,make,get,let,need,someth" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Similar to cron-apt, I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/lenny/apticron&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;apticron&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-04T20:03:12.753" EntityChunks="" Id="4285" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T20:03:12.753" NounPhrases=" similar cron,use" OwnerUserId="984" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="5" Verbs="apticron" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;For our Windows boxes we have a local WSUS server, and a standard window to apply the monthly patches.  For the Linux systems (RHEL) we have a RHN satelite server on campus that they are all joined to.  That provides a nice dashboard of every joined system that you administer, as well as the unapplied updates for each system.  For those that are in puppet, we push out a script that auto applies patches during a regular window and sends an email notification with the results.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-31T13:08:30.663" EntityChunks="" Id="16189" LastActivityDate="2009-05-31T13:08:30.663" NounPhrases=" window box local wsu server  standard window appli monthli patch   linux system,rhel,provid nice dashboard everi join system administ  well unappli updat system   puppet,script auto appli patch,regular window,email" OwnerUserId="3356" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="join,provid,push,send,result" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;On OpenSuSE Linux, SLES, and Novell OES (all SuSE-based products), we've got a script that runs zypper and looks for packages that need to be updated. When it finds one, it submits a ticket to JIRA and assigns it to the sysadmins. When we install the updates, we close the ticket, which leaves an audit trail that tells us when it was installed and by whom. This can be reconciled/confirmed with the zypper and sudo logs, which are centralized on a syslogging server. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-06-05T04:01:09.440" EntityChunks="one" Id="20262" LastActivityDate="2009-06-05T04:01:09.440" NounPhrases="linux,sle,novel,base product,script run,zypper,ticket jira assign sysadmin,instal updat,ticket,leav audit trail,us,reconcil,zypper sudo,central syslog server" OwnerUserId="8021" ParentId="3" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="suse,get,find,submit,tell" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't think it's common per se. However, as soon as you start using enterprise storage controllers, whether that be SAN's or standalone RAID controllers, you'll generally want to adhere to their compatibility list rather closely.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;You may be able to save some bucks on the sticker price by buying a cheap range of disks, but that's probably one of the last areas I'd want to save money on - given the importance of data in most scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;In other words, explicit incompatibility is very uncommon, but explicit compatibility adherence is recommendable.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:56:20.070" EntityChunks="one" Id="5" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T07:56:20.070" NounPhrases="howev,enterpris storag control,san standalon raid control,gener,adher compat list,buck sticker price,cheap rang disk,one last area,money,import data scenario     word" OwnerUserId="24" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="think,start,use,want,may,save,buy,probabl,want,save,give,recommend" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;The answer as always is &quot;it depends&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;For certain enterprise storage (say EMC), the vendor will specifically qualify drives and even go to the extent of loading custom firmware. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;As Mark says, I find it to be the best when you follow a vendor's approved list if there is one. The initial cost savings is outweighed by the time spent trying to hunt down gremlins.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:22:10.837" EntityChunks="one" Id="74" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:22:10.837" NounPhrases="certain enterpris storag,extent load custom,firmwar      mark,outweigh time,hunt gremlin" OwnerUserId="97" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="2" Verbs="answer,depend,say,drive,go,say,find,follow,list,save,spend" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Even for non-RAID, plain-old desktop hard drives, buying drives from the vendor (at the expected ridiculous markup) can often make a difference.  For example, Apple is careful to only ship drives that are actually capable of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.apple.com/archives/darwin-dev/2005/Feb/msg00072.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;honoring Mac OS X's &lt;code&gt;F_FULLSYNC&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;fcntl()&lt;/code&gt; flag&lt;/a&gt;, which goes a long way towards making sure things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/timemachine.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Time Machine&lt;/a&gt; backups work reliably.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Again, this is plain vanilla &lt;em&gt;desktop&lt;/em&gt; use with no RAID involved.  Anything more complex than that and you definitely want to buy, if not the vendor's own over-priced drives, then at least drive models that you know for sure are on the vendor's &quot;approved&quot; list.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;So, to answer your question, is it common?  I'd say, yes, more common than you might think, even beyond the enterprise realm.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="1" CommentCount="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T12:41:26.127" EntityChunks="" Id="619" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T12:41:26.127" NounPhrases="raid,drive vendor,ridicul markup,appl care ship,actual capabl,honor,mac,flag   goe,sure thing,time machin,backup work reliabl      plain vanilla,use,raid,anyth complex definit,vendor price drive,least drive model,sure vendor,list      answer question,ye,enterpris realm" OwnerUserId="456" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="13" Verbs="buy,expect,make,differ,drive,make,want,know,say,may,think" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, I have encountered this with low-end cards and buggy drivers. However, &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;, not on an up-to-date Adaptec rebranded card. Wow is all I can say. One thing to consider, maybe it is more a bug with the drive than the RAID controller.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;I don't have a good answer, but since you seem to have exhausted most of your options other than replacing the card, (and replacing the drives did the trick) here's a few ideas you can consider for your troubleshooting:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;ul&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The WD drives were RE (RAID Edition) drives, right?&lt;/strong&gt; The time limited error recovery is important, so if you don't have that and the drive is attempting to recover the sector, you are going to get a looooong pause from that drive. If the RAID controller is being patient and not dropping the drive you'll have a big problem on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the SMART data on the drives&lt;/strong&gt; you removed and see if there is anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#10;&lt;/ul&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Another comment about the importance of time limited error recovery (TLER) feature, from NAS / RAID vendor support:&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#10;  &lt;p&gt;As I mention before, we always suggest customers to use enterprise level drives if they use the drives in RAID settings. &lt;strong&gt;Enterprise level drives have more consistent responding time so that the RAID will be safer.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="4" CreationDate="2009-04-30T16:42:53.610" EntityChunks="" Id="1238" LastActivityDate="2010-08-24T09:41:35.597" LastEditDate="2010-08-24T09:41:35.597" LastEditorUserId="1" NounPhrases="  ye,howev     date adaptec rebrand card,one thing,mayb,bug drive raid control     good answer,sinc seem,idea,wd drive  raid edit,right   time limit error,import,attempt recov sector,looooong paus drive,raid control patient drop,big problem hand       check smart data drive,remov,anyth interest        anoth comment import time limit error,tler,featur,mention,enterpris level drive use drive raid,enterpris level" OwnerUserId="762" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="6" Verbs="say,consid,consid,drive,drive,go,get,see,support,suggest,use,set,consist" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;You have a SAS controller, that might be the problem. While SAS protocol can be used to tunnel ATA commands the signaling at physical level is a bit different (SAS uses higher voltage and wider differential). Almost all controllers are able to speak directly to SATA drives, but if there's a (big? crappy?) backplane in the middle the signal might be disrupted. Usually in the enterprise world attaching SATA drivers &lt;i&gt;directly&lt;/i&gt; to a SAS controller is not officially supported, you should use an interposer (a small logic board that connects directly to the disk that on one side understands the full SAS protocol, on the other speaks ATA - in this way the backplane carries the higher SAS signaling).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: mixing SAS and SATA drives on the same backplane tends to fail, because the signaling of all drives (including SAS) is lowered to SATA level.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-04T14:49:19.827" EntityChunks="one" Id="4053" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T14:49:19.827" NounPhrases=" sa control,higher voltag,almost control,speak directli sata,big  crappi   backplan middl signal,world attach sata driver,sa control offici support,directli disk,one side,full sa protocol,way backplan,higher sa signal      somewhat relat  mix sa sata drive backplan,lower sata level" OwnerUserId="1166" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="2" Verbs="may,problem,use,speak,may,disrupt,attach,use,connect,understand,speak,mix" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't dream of using SATA disks for a server - none of them have the expected duty cycle of a server quality drive and they don't have the rich command set that SCSI/SAS has for monitoring drive performance and health. Lenovo servers are cheap and great if you have lots of servers with none of them really that important but there's a reason that HP's 300-series servers account for 40% of the market - they work. In particular their 'SmartArray' disk controllers are matchless in reliability and performance and their pre-failure guarantee is a welcome addition. Not the cheapest but how much is your time worth? I've been buying their (well Compaq first tbh) servers for twenty years now and have no issue whatsoever buying the 500-800 new ones a year that I do. Seriously check them out.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2009-05-04T22:51:51.570" EntityChunks="first,twenti year,one year" Id="4377" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T22:51:51.570" NounPhrases=" dream use,sata disk server,none,duti,rich command set scsi sa monitor drive perform,health,lenovo,server,cheap great lot server,none,import reason,hp     seri server account     market   work,smartarray,guarante welcom addit,cheapest much time,first tbh,server,issu whatsoev" OwnerUserId="1435" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="4" Verbs="expect,drive,set,monitor,perform,pre,buy,compaq,buy,check" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;Most probably &lt;strong&gt;your WD drives need a firmware update&lt;/strong&gt;. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-307.ibm.com/pc/support/site.wss/document.do?sitestyle=lenovo&amp;amp;lndocid=MIGR-72219&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this IBM note&lt;/a&gt; for downloading and applyig the update. As you can see from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.lenovo.com/ibmdl/pub/pc/pccbbs/thinkcentre_software/fabhdd01sr17.txt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;, the WD drives are far from the only ones with problems. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;If you are going to put your drives in a taxing server environment, you are bound to run into more problems than in a typical enthusiast desktop configuration. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Could you maybe comment on why you chose to go with the desktop class &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hitachigst.com/portal/site/en/products/deskstar/P7K500/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Deskstar&lt;/a&gt; series of drives instead of the Enterprise/RAID class &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hitachigst.com/portal/site/en/products/ultrastar/A7K1000/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ultrastar&lt;/a&gt; series? Do you feel the extra cost is not worth the added reliability and speed?&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="2" CreationDate="2009-06-01T08:12:42.400" EntityChunks="one" Id="16640" LastActivityDate="2009-06-01T13:39:31.250" LastEditDate="2009-06-01T13:39:31.250" LastEditorUserId="4979" NounPhrases=" probabl,wd drive,see,ibm note,download,applyig updat,wd,far one problem,drive tax server,run problem,desktop class,deskstar,drive,raid class,ultrastar,seri,extra cost worth ad reliabl speed" OwnerUserId="4979" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="1" Verbs="need,ibm,see,instruct,go,put,bind,could,mayb,choose,go,enterpris,feel" />
  <row Body="&lt;p&gt;As an engineer that works with RAID controllers, I can say that it is not uncommon for some brands of drives to have problems with certain RAID controllers.  Every drive has its particular quirks, and any drive model listed on the controller's &quot;compatible devices&quot; list will have its quirks accounted for by the controller.  For a drive model to show up on the list, it has to meet the controller manufacturer's standards for performance and reliability.  Any drive not on this list might work, but since it hasn't gone through the same rigorous testing as &quot;approved&quot; devices, YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;In particular, the SATA protocol allows for vendor-specific (non-standardized) commands that can be defined by the drive or the controller.  In your case, you are might be seeing a controller that is expecting a drive to respond to a particular proprietary command or a drive that is expecting to see a proprietary command that never arrives.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is that your problematic drives do not behave very well under certain stressful workloads, and the behavior you see was enough for Adaptec/IBM to not list that drive model as supported.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, storage protocols (SATA, SAS, etc) are not as nice as other standardized interfaces (USB, PCI, etc) where all you need is a bus and a device that speak the same language and everything's fine.  Especially when it comes to Enterprise-grade equipment, device manufacturers and drive manufacturers spend a lot of collaborative time and energy ensuring that customers get the best possible performance out of the configurations used by the majority of customers (that is, using drives off of the &quot;supported devices&quot; list).  A drive not on that list may have been designed to perform optimally with a different brand of controller, and the errors you are seeing are a side effect of the optimization.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;" CodeblockCount="0" CommentCount="0" CreationDate="2010-02-22T18:05:03.060" EntityChunks="" Id="115488" LastActivityDate="2010-02-22T18:05:03.060" NounPhrases=" engin work raid control,uncommon brand drive problem,everi,model list control,quirk account control,drive model show list,control manufactur standard perform reliabl   drive list,sinc gone rigor test,approv,ymmv,sata protocol,vendor specif,control,drive respond particular proprietari command drive,proprietari command,anoth possibl problemat,certain stress workload  behavior,protocol,sata,sa,nice standard interfac,usb  pci,devic speak languag everyth,fine   especi,enterpris grade equip,devic manufactur drive manufactur spend lot collabor time energi ensur custom,best possibl,configur,major custom   use drive,support,list    drive list,optim differ brand control,error,side effect" OwnerUserId="35689" ParentId="2" PostTypeId="2" Score="0" Verbs="say,drive,drive,meet,may,work,sinc,go,allow,may,see,expect,drive,expect,possibl,see,need,come,spend,get,perform,use,list,may,design,perform,see" />
  </posts>